现在对你们来说还不算太晚
It's not too late for you.
我的提议依然有效
My offer still stands.
要么加入我们
You can join us...
要么去死
or you can die.
转身
Turn.
为什么
Why?
为什么拍照
Why the pictures?
之后给你做雕塑
Sculpt you, after.
什么之后
After what?
就是之后
After.
《行尸走肉》
我知道的事
我知道我不知道的事
我不知道的事
我知道你是叛徒
I'm well-aware ‭you're the fifth columner.
绿包  红漆  工人的枪
Green duffel, red paint, workers' guns.
不需要图灵级别的解密
Doesn't require Turing-grade decryption
就能得知这一真相
to grok the truth that you're the traitor
你是跟"亚山神"勾结的叛徒
creeping and colluding with AHK.
这是我创的首字母缩写词
It's an acronym I've concocted --
亚历山大  山顶寨  神之国
Alexandria, Hilltop, Kingdom.
我本来想用"神亚山"
I considered going with KAH,
但这个词太像象声词了
but it remains ‭a hair too onomatopoeiac.
尼根本人亲自安排我
I've been charged ‭by no less than Negan himself
找到解决灾难的办法
with cracking the very calamity
而你大有可能是主要诱因
you more than likely had a heavy hand in creating.
所以我需要你立刻停止并终止
So I need you to cease and desist
一切背叛和背后捅刀
all betrayals and backstabbery,
打幌子和叛变行为
fronting and Judas-ness A.S.A.P.
作为交换  我不会把我知道的信息
In exchange, ‭I offer to keep what I know
告诉尼根和其他人
from Negan and the others.
救世军完了
The Saviors are finished.
尼根完了
Negan's finished.
这地方
And this place...
过去的辉煌
what it's been...
全完了
that's all over.
食物和水短缺  工人很愤怒
Food and water's runnin' low, workers are angry,
救世军心慌意乱
the Saviors, they're gettin' scared.
这地方必将陷落
And this place is gonna fall,
你要想站在获胜的一方  唯一要做的
and all you have to do to be on the winning side
就是顺势而为
is to stand down.
什么都不要做
All you have to do is nothing.
等着
Wait.
静观其变
Let it play out.
你能做到吗
Can you do that?
你见过这里发生的事
You've seen what happens here...
听到过尖叫
heard the screams...
闻到过烧伤的皮肤
smelled the burning skin.
你现在还没杀人
You don't got blood on your hands yet,
但那很快了
but that's comin'.
一旦你做了那些事  你就成了坏人
Once you do those things, you become those things,
再也无法回头了
and there's no goin' back.
再也无法忘记
No forgettin' it.
我的目的就是保命
What cranks my shaft is bein' safe.
而在这里  我安全
And here, me bein' safe
意味着很多人也安全
means a whole lot of other people are safe.
我常想到这点
I think about that a great deal.
对  我是尼根
Yes, I'm Negan...
这并不完美  但我们是救世军
and it ain't perfect, but we are Saviors.
我们要救人
We save.
如我所说
Like I said...
你的叛变活动未被察觉
your Cloak-and-Dagger's on the Q.T.
只要你不做任何伤害墙内人的事
All I ask is that you do nothin' that results in harm to anyone inside these walls,
我就不会揭发你
and it'll stay that way.
你觉得能撑多久
What do you think?
一天吧
A day.
也许两天
Maybe two.
尤金
Eugene.
我需要帮忙
I could use a little help.
进来一下好吗
Can you come in?
他情况更糟了
He's getting worse.
是一种感染
It's an infection.
也可能是多种
Maybe more than one.
在攻击他的脏器
It's attacking his organs.
某个脏器衰竭只是时间问题
It's only a matter of time until one fails.
真希望我们能有些该死的药
Just wish ‭we had some damn meds.
真希望他没有
I wish he hadn't
参与设计这么拙劣的陷阱把我们困在这
assisted in the ill-conceived caper to trap us in here.
我还希望有彩色糖果吃
I also wish for Razzles,
但如果愿望都能实现  那可就...
but if wishes ‭were horses and all that...
怎么  你觉得这都是他的错吗
What, you think this is his fault?
没错
It is.
不是全部
Not the whole of it,
但他是叛军的一员
but he was ‭a member of the campaign.
我能理解他
I do get it...
但我不会忘记的
but I shan't forget it.
你陪陪他好吗
Would you sit with him?
你干什么
How's that?
我去市场看看
I'm gonna head to the marketplace,
看能否找到草药
see if they have any herbs down there,
给他试试草药
try some Eastern medicine on him.
他不能没人看护
He shouldn't be alone.
-而且他是你的朋友  -旅伴而已
- And he's your friend. - Traveling Companion.
好吧  你希望他死吗
Okay. Do you want him to die?
不
No.
我很快就回来
I'll be back soon.
坐吧
Sit.
你脸色比我还差
You look worse than me.
我不这么想
I don't appreciate that,
因为你看起来好像土豆烩大便
because you look like a potato and shit casserole.
坐
Sit.
你能帮我把卡森医生救出去吗
Are you gonna help me get Dr. Carson out of here?
鉴于这栋建筑目前被行尸团团围住
Given that this building is currently surrounded by a Wilkes-Barre of walkers,
我认为无法逃离
I don't see an escape attempt
除非使用陷你于这种糟糕境地的
without putting to use the same flawed technique of innards
那种漏洞百出的内脏涂身方法
which landed you in your status-quo piss-poor condition.
你提出这种要求时可能忘了
What you may have forgotten in your request
我只是个小人物
is that I am a small person
我不会为任何人冒险  除了我自己
who does not stick his neck out for anyone other than himself.
我只在自己的车道上行驶
I stick firmly within my lane
不需要信号灯  不管是手动还是自动
without any need for a signal, hand or automatic.
我只希望你能做正确的事
All I want is for you to do the right thing.
正确的事该怎么定义
And what is said definition on that?
我从来没有搞清楚过
Can't say I ever sussed it out.
对有些人正确的事  对另一些人可能是噩梦
Right for some can be downright horrific for others,
就因为熟知这点
and knowing that has kept me vertical
所以我还站着  而别人倒下了
when so many have gone horizontal.
这需要信念  自我信任
It requires faith, trusting yourself.
相信上帝就在你心中
Believing that God is inside of you...
指导你
guiding you...
知道他对我们的命运各有安排
and knowing that he has a plan for all of us.
那很难吗
Is that so hard?
那很荒谬
It's absurd.
是吗
Is it?
你相信科学
You're a man of science...
不久之前还不相信
who not too long ago would've found it
死人可以重新行走于世上
impossible to believe that the dead could walk.
所以也许
So maybe...
也有可能相信
maybe it's not impossible to believe
当那一刻来临时  你会知道
that you will know what the right thing is
怎么做才是正确的
when the time comes.
然后
And then...
你会...做的
you will -- you'll act.
有发现
Got something.
好像是一辆卡车
Looked like a truck,
但是开过了水塔看不到了
but I lost visual from the water tower.
是我们的人
It's one of ours.
塔尼娅  你好
Tanya, hello.
你说一周  已经一周了
You said a week. It's been a week.
我们的约定呢  我的音响呢
Our deal? My boombox?
是的  我是说...
Well, yes, I mean --
你修好了吗
Did you fix it?
你是认真的吗
A-are you serious?
是的
Yeah.
还没修好
Well, it's not ready.
我们被行尸掐着喉咙
Our neck is ‭in the noose of the deceased,
情况越来越恶劣
and it is tightening with every ticktock.
你一点都不担心我们被困在这里吗
Are you not distressed that we're trapped?
我以前就被困在这里
I was already trapped here.
明天之前给我  尤金
You've got until tomorrow, Eugene,
然后再议
and then we renegotiate.
等等
Wait.
虽然没有修好  但是能不能把
Would it be possible to take possession of the second bottle
第二瓶先预付给我
despe the delivery delinquency?
我们说好的是先给你一瓶
The deal was one bottle up front
修好后再给你一瓶
and one bottle after you fix it.
我很需要
I need it.
你要用来当燃料之类的吗
You making it into jet fuel or something?
晚上我都要喝个1.5盎司左右
I've taken to throwing 1.5 fluid ounces down my gullet most P.M.S
才能够进入越来越不安稳的睡眠
as a necessary requirement to catching ‭some increasingly elusive Z's.
所以我需要这些傻笑饮料
Ergo, I need the giggle juice.
我明白
I get it.
我也需要助眠
I need help sleeping, too.
我不明白
I don't get it.
你明白
Yes, you do.
你帮助他们  尤金
You help them, Eugene.
你帮助他
You help him.
我试图阻止过
I tried to stop this.
我和弗兰基来找你
Me and Frankie, we came to you,
寻求帮助
and we asked you for your help.
你本可以让这个地方变得不一样
You could've changed this place into something else,
变得更好
something better.
但你只为自己着想
But you took care of you,
现在你得承受后果
and now you've got to live with that.
我希望这能帮你
I hope this helps.
但其实帮不了
But it won't.
尼根要见你
Negan wants you.
我们的人很快就到救世堂
Our people are gonna be at the Sanctuary soon,
要求他们投降
asking for their surrender.
我们快成功了
We're almost there.
所以我们才要这么做
That's why we do it.
我们要确保成功
We make it happen.
我们与上方窗户的人交火来掩护你
So we cover you with crossfire from the upper windows,
你开车穿过尸群
you crash the truck into the walkers
撞向大楼
and through to the building.
对  撞个豁口  救世军自助餐
Yep, crack it open, Savior buffet.
你确定工人会逃掉  到楼上去吗
You know the workers will make it away, up the stairs?
他们在大楼的另一边  应该能逃掉
They're on the other side of the building. They should make it.
你确定吗
You sure?
我们这样做之后
After we do this,
他们别无选择  只能投降
their only choice is to give up.
这有风险  他们也许能看到卡车来
It's risky. They could see the truck comin'.
救世军的仓库里
There weren't any more weapons
已经没有武器了  不是吗
at the Saviors' warehouse, right?
火箭筒没火箭弹了
No more rockets for the RPGs.
我们只能利用现有的东西
We work with what we got.
你们还有我
You got me.
以及其他狙击手
Other snipers, too.
如果救世军看到你们来  我们负责掩护
Saviors see you comin', we got you covered,
不惜一切代价
whatever it takes.
我想了结这事
I want it done.
我想了结他们
I want them done.
很好
Good.
我们到底行不行动
So, we doin' this or what?
我们为什么不按原计划  耐心等待呢
W-Why don't we just wait it out like we planned?
米琼恩说得对
Michonne's right.
你的提议太冒险了  可能会出岔子
What you're talking about is risky. Things could go bad.
带音箱的那辆卡车差点引走了尸群
The truck with the speakers almost took all those walkers away.
差点出了岔子  还可能发生其他意外
It almost did go bad. Something else could.
就算不出意外
Even if it don't,
我们也失去神之国的战士了
we don't got ‭the Kingdom fighters no more.
如果救世军决心抵抗
I mean, if the Saviors want to put up a fight,
我们也没有足够的人手迫使他们投降
we don't got the numbers to make 'em surrender.
所以瑞克去找拾荒者谈判了
That's why Rick's talking to the Scavengers.
你中了枪  他们骗了我们
You got shot. They lied to us.
现在你倒相信他们了
You -- You believe 'em now?
我相信瑞克·格兰姆斯
I believe in Rick Grimes.
我本可以做点什么的
I could've done something...
更快了结此事
sooner, to end this.
我知道海边旅馆有武器  而我却在等
I knew about those weapons at Oceanside, and I waited.
我什么都没做
I didn't do shit about it.
不管你参不参与
With or without you,
我都不会让那重演
I'm not ‭letting that happen again.
那我就不参与
Then it's without me.
我退出
I'm out.
我们还有些车停在东边哨点附近
We got somcars parked near the east-side lookout.
你可以开一辆回家
You can take one and go home.
你要留下吗
You staying?
你也同意这样做吗
You good with all this?
是我起的头
I helped get this started.
我得确保成功
Got to see it through.
你觉得在这冒险
You think it's easier to come out here and risk
比回去等机会更容易
than to stay back there and wait.
我明白  我以前也这么想
And I get it -- ‭I used to believe that, too.
但事实是  有时你必须等待
Thing is sometimes, you just have to wait.
有时你没办法知道
Sometimes you don't get to know.
我只希望自己不是在
I just wish it didn't take
看着萨沙从棺材里出来后  才明白这一点
seeing Sasha walk out of that coffin to realize it.
好了
Come on.
走吧
Let's go.
如果不尽快解决
If things don't get fixed soon,
会死很多人
a lot of people are gonna die.
我的人
My people.
当然了  我不会死
Not me, of course.
不管发生什么  我都能活下来
I'm livin' no matter what.
我太擅长做这种事了
I am too good at this shit.
但是其他人
But others...
我不能眼看着他们死
I can't have that.
我不想看着我的人被打死  被撕碎
I don't want to see people get shot up, chewed up,
再去咬其他人
and chewing up the rest.
我不想看着你被咬死  尤金
I don't want to see you get eaten, Eugene.
这个地方
This place,
建立于集中和组织力量的基础之上
it's about pooling and organizing strength.
而你
And you...
我的朋友  非常强大
my friend, are strong.
你的眼睛和长发间的那个海绵体器官
That spongy organ between your eyes and your spectacular mullet
非常强大
is strong,
我只想让你知道
and I just want to make sure that you know...
我知道这一点
that I know that.
当做我知道吧
Consider me made.
我们的想法完全一致
Our pages are utterly and completely one and the same.
尤金
Eugene...
我是想要握手的
I was going for a handshake.
站起来
Stand up.
我知道你在困惑什么
Now, I can see where you'd be confused,
因为我很少做这种破事
as I rarely do that shit.
握手代表着相互尊重
A handshake is a sign of mutual respect.
能得到我尊重的人并不是很多
Not many people get that from me.
有些工作需要去做了
There's work that needs getting to.
关掉引擎
Hey, cut that engine.
再靠近的话会引来院子里的行尸
Any closer, you'll draw walkers from the yard.
给
Here.
你们吸引火力  我们反击
You take fire from the windows, we fire back.
走吧
Come on.
斜道旁有个掩护点
There's a spot for cover by the chutes.
你准备好了吗
You up for this?
我来这是想亲眼见证一下
I came here 'cause I wanted to see things for myself.
我想知道计划管用
I wanted to know ‭that things were gonna work.
但是你知道吗
But you know what?
我不能确认这一点
I don't get to know that.
我们都不能
None of us do.
我知道的是计划目前奏效了
What I do know is that things are working now.
所以也许
So maybe...
我们只能坚信
we just need to trust
计划会一直奏效
that things are gonna keep working,
因为这件事
because this...
我们即将要做的事
what we're about to do...
不值得我们冒生命危险
it's not worth risking us.
对我来说值得
It is for me.
真的值得
Just is.
我希望能成功
I hope it works.
我真的希望能成功  但我做不到
I-I really, really do, but I-I can't do it.
真的做不到
I just can't.
那你就不该去做
Then you shouldn't.
我们有摩根和狙击手
We got Morgan and the snipers.
我们能做到
We can do this.
是啊
Yeah.
我们能做到
We will.
供日后记录用的录音
Audio recording for transcription.
紧急行动手册  第一次分录
Emergency operations manual, first entry.
栅栏被围攻时的解决方案
Countermeasure approach for fence incursion.
行尸爆发  距之前的栅栏40到50英尺
High pop of undead, good 40, 50 deep to the former fence.
记得以后附上紧急粘合音频滑翔机草图
Note to accompany schematics for audio glider emergency binder.
音频滑翔机已开启声音
Audio glider activated for sound,
使用95分贝音乐转移尸群注意力
utilizing music as 96 decibel redirection,
吸引所有活跃行尸远离全部出口
drawing active deceased along with it away from all exits,
立即创造出逃生通道  以便永久引走尸群
allowing immediate free passage for permanent redirection,
如果成功的话
if successful.
划掉前面的"如果"  改为"成功之后"
Scratch the if -- when -- when successful.
没错
Hell, yes.
别转身
Don't turn around.
我到了
I'm here.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
南边哨点  一切就绪
South lookout -- ready for go.
东边哨点  就绪
East lookout, ready.
北边哨点  就绪
North lookout, ready.
西边哨点  就绪
West lookout, ready.
站起来  远离那东西
Get up, back away from that thing.
我叫你离远点
Back away from it!
我是想救人  德怀特
I'm attempting to save people, Dwight.
杀了我  就是杀了一群无辜的人
And killin' me is killin' a great many innocents.
等这只小鸟出巢
When this bird slips its surly bounds,
它就能引走那些冰冷的行尸
it's gonna Pied Piper away their cold corpses
解放这里
and free this place.
而尼根会杀了瑞克  达里尔和罗西塔
And Negan will kill Rick and Daryl and Rosita
还有你的那些老朋友们
and all your old friends.
他们只是曾经的旅伴  仅此而已
They're former traveling companions, nothing more.
我和他们合作
I'm working with them
是为了让他们和这里的人活着
to keep them ‭and the people here alive.
我们可以杀掉尼根
We can get rid of Negan.
只杀尼根
Just Negan.
我们马上就要成功了
And we're almost there.
尼根轻易死不了  德怀特
Negan ain't the dyin' type, Dwight.
-但你死定了  尤金  -是的
- Oh, but you are, Eugene. - I am.
正因此我才没有退开
That's exactly why I've not yet stepped back, as it were.
在我看来  我可以选择两种命运
By my reckoning, I have two selects on facin' my fate.
第一种是中止放飞滑翔机
One, I abort launch on this glider,
让这里继续困在行尸的獠牙利齿之下
don't free this place from the stranglehold of cold teeth/tongues,
而尼根很有可能会处死我
and Negan will likely execute me
还认为他是帮了我的忙
as what he considers to be a personal favor.
或者  我可以选第二种命运
Or I could go for ‭what's behind door number two,
赌一把你这旧时盟友不会在我身后开枪
take my chances being shot in the back by a sometime-ally,
尽管以前我曾伤害过你
despite any injury I may have caused in the past
冲你裆部狠狠咬了一口
by delivering a chomp down on your chode.
现在
Now!
达里尔  南边安全
Daryl, you're clear to the south.
你和塔拉应该回家了
You and Tara should head home.
走吧  快走  走吧
Let's go! Move it! Let go!
撤退  快走
Fall back! Move!
快撤
Move!
撤退  快撤  快撤
Fall back! Move! Move!
快撤  快撤
Move! Move!
答案是不行
The answer is no!
我永远不会  绝不能同意你的方案
I will never, not on your Nelly, be on board with your plan.
你的邀约已被拒绝
Your invite is declined.
我不会沦落到萨沙或你的下场
I will not end up like Sasha or you.
你们都做出了选择
You both made your choices,
选了多数人会觉得正确的选择
what I imagine most will calculate as the right thing,
掷着二十面骰子把自己玩死
rolled your D20s and came up dead
此骰子源自《龙与地下城》桌游
眼看着死期将至
and seemingly soon to be.
恕我不能盲从
I cannot do the same.
你可以随便批判我  但我看得清清楚楚
Now, judge me if you choose, but I'm seeing 20 for 20,
心里安安稳稳  听得明明白白
I'm feeling 10 for 10, I'm receiving 5 by 5
不冒风险就是保全性命
that staying safe means staying alive,
只要能确保活着  我做什么都行
and I'm A-okay ‭with doing whatever it takes to lock that down.
所以我会听从尼根
So I will obey Negan.
我不会掩护任何人的叛变
I will not cover for anyone's U-turn on loyalties,
我还会确保
and I will damn well make sure
卡森医生舒舒服服地待在这
that Dr. Carson stays cozy, comfy right here
以备我对他医术的不时之需
in case I ever require his healing expertise!
我不会感到自责
And I won't feel bad about it.
因为我会活下去
Because I will survive.
这是我血液里的印记
It's in ‭my biological imperative.
是我唯一知道的事情
It's all I know how to do.
那得用很多弹药
It'll take an ass-load of ammo.
是的
It will.
即使枪法精湛小心克制
Even with shot discipline and P and Q minding.
我的造弹专家能把枪装满吗
Can my bullet maker fill my guns back up?
如果你把机器给我  让我操作机器
If you give my machines to me or me to my machines...
答案是肯定的
that is an affirmative.
你知道等我解决完瑞克给我添的麻烦
You do realize the storm of shit I'm gonna dump on Rick
我就会给瑞克添大麻烦吧
as soon as I am clear of the shit storm he dumped on me.
我知道
I do, indeed.
我的天  尤金
Goddamn, Eugene.
你作为除了我以外最重要的人  有何感想
How does it feel to be the second-most important person here?
拯救这些好人的感觉如何
How does it feel ‭to save these good people?
感觉很好
It feels great.
还有个要紧事
Got something else of urgency for you.
我也帮你解决了
another item solved.
除了能冲出尸群
More than a way out
装满子弹  还有别的惊喜吗
and a promise of bullets on the way?
天啊  尤金
Jesus, Eugene,
你太棒了
you are magnificent.
是的
I am.
是什么事
So, what is it?
告诉我
Tell me.
怎么了
What? ‭
我们守住了楼梯
We have the stairs.
但行尸占据了楼下
But the dead ones have the lower level --
全被占了
the whole thing.
不会太久的
Not much longer.
尤金想出了让我们摆脱困境的方法
See, Eugene has solved us a way out of this mess.
而且  他说他还有更好的消息
And...he actually says he has a topper.
是吗
Yeah?
我能修好内部对讲系统
I think I could fix the intercom system.
那能...
Which, uh...
完全改变这里的通讯现状
would absolutely change the face of communications here.
就这
That's it?
抱歉  这种事
Sorry. That kind of thing, uh...
令我兴奋
well, cranks my shaft.
我不打扰你们办事了
I'll leave you to the last action item.
该之后了
Time for after.
别抗拒
Subdue!
我现在要走出去
I'm walking out now,
我走出去意味着你们都得死
and me walking out means all of you die.
我的人  他们数量很多
My people -- there's a lot of them --
今天不会进攻  但我们会进攻的
won't attack today, but we will attack.
你们可以玩游戏  画画
You can play your games, draw your pictures,
做他妈的雕塑  但我要走了
sculpt whatever shit you want, but I am leaving!
在那之后
After that...
也许你们应该逃走
maybe you should just run.
玩够了吗
We done?
是的
Yes.
加入你
Join you.
然后呢
What then?
救世堂被包围了
The Sanctuary is surrounded.
行尸
Walkers.
基地被围得水泄不通
20 deep around the compound.
你和我去那里
You'll come with me there...
等其他人和我们碰头
we'll wait till the others meet us.
见面后  我们要求副手们投降
When they do, we'll ask the lieutenants to surrender.
我们一起要求
All of us, together.
然后我杀了尼根  独自杀
Then I kill Negan, me alone.
成交吗
We have a deal?
事成后  救世军的东西归我们
After, ‭Saviors' things our things.
你同意我就同意
Yes and yes.
东西属于我们所有人
It'll be all of ours.
你能拿到四分之一
You'll get a fourth.
-一半  -四分之一
- Half. ‭- A fourth.
四分之一  让我给你做个雕塑
Fourth, and I sculpt you after.
为我站着  脱掉裤子
Stand for me, those off.
解开绳子  不准做雕塑
These off, no sculpting.
立刻把鞋和衣服还我
My boots and my clothes now.
四分之一
Fourth.
狙击手  上报
Snipers, report in.
我是瑞克·格兰姆斯
This is Rick Grimes.
有人收到吗
Does anybody copy?